Guide to the Elwood Kalin Papers 1954-1983
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Elwood Kalin Papers
1954-1983
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 572
Kalin, Elwood
4 containers. 4.5 linear feet of shelf space.
The papers of Elwood Kalin consist of notes, memoranda, correspondence, and various working papers regarding his experiences as a horticulturalist and with floral presentations.
Elwood Walter Kalin served as a professor of Horticulture at Washington State University from 1946 to 1983. Kalin was born at Detroit in 1917. He received the Bachelor of Science degree from Michigan State University in 1939, and the Master of Science degree form Purdue University in 1942. In 1953, he was granted the Ph.D. degree from Purdue.
Kalin worked briefly at Purdue and at the University of New Hampshire from 1943 through 1946. His employment at Washington State University began during 1946-47, with assignments that divided his time between an experiment station and classroom work. He continued this arrangement until his retirement in 1983.
Kalin was best known for the floral arrangement shows and classes that he arranged for the public.
Elwood Walter Kalin died at Pullman, WA in 1993.
The papers of Elwood Kalin consist of notes, memoranda, correspondence, and various working papers.
The first series within the papers is concerned with his work as a teacher of classes in horticulture, greenhouse growing, and floral presentations. A second series concerns Kalin's long involvement with a national competition for floral presentations. The third series is a subject file sequence, also concern, chiefly with the growing and presentation of decorative flowers.
This collection is open for research use.
The papers of Elwood Kalin were donated to the Washington State University Libraries in 1985 by Mr. Kalin.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Kalin, Elwood --Archives
Washington State University--Faculty--Archives; Horticulture -- Research--Archives; Flower shows -- Judging; Greenhouse management--Archives; Greenhouse plants--Research--Archives; Flowers -- Research; Flower arrangement--Research
Arts and Humanities; Agriculture; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: Horticulture
  - Horticulture 235: Chrysanthemums, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Horticulture 235: CO2, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Horticulture 235: Conservatory Plants, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Horticulture 235: Fungicide Facts, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Air Conditioning, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Arrangement and Spacing, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Boilers, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Construction, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Fertilizers, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Flower, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Fuels, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Location and Sites, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Horticulture 235: Greenhouse Watering, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Horticulture 235: Injection Fertilization, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Horticulture 235: Insect Control--Aerosols, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Horticulture 235: Mineral nutrition, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Horticulture 235: Mist Propagation, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Horticulture 235: Plant Tissue Tests, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Horticulture 235: Plastic Greenhouse, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Horticulture 235: Soil Preparation for Greenhouse, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Horticulture 235: Soil Testing, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Horticulture 235: Soil Sterilization, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Horticulture 235: Soluble Salts, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Horticulture 235: Water Relations in Plants, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Horticulture 235-236: Laboratory Material, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Horticulture 236: Greenhouse Management, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Horticulture 437: Carnations, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Horticulture 437: Chrysanthemums, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Horticulture 437: Poinsettias, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Horticulture 437: Snapdragons, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Horticulture 438: African Violet, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Horticulture 438: Azaleas, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Horticulture 438: Bedding Plants, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Horticulture 438: Begonias, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Horticulture 438: Calceolarias, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Horticulture 438: Cinerarias, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Horticulture 438: Dutch Iris, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Horticulture 438: Forcing Lilies, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Horticulture 438: Geraniums and Fuchsia, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Horticulture 438: Greenhouse Rose, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Horticulture 438: Gloxinias, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Horticulture 438: Hyacinths, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Horticulture 438: Hydrangeas, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Horticulture 438: Narcissus, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Horticulture 438: Orchids, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Horticulture 438: Palms, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Horticulture 438: Tulips, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Series 2: Intercollegiate Flower Judging
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1956-58 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Intercollegiate Flower Judging, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Series 3: Subject Files
  - Commencement at WSU, 1955-58 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Flower Arranging, undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Flower Arranging, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Manuscript: American Style of Flower Arranging, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Manuscript: Correspondence, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Manuscript: Flower Arranging--American Style, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Manuscript: The Challenging of Flower Arranging, undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Pictures for American Flower Arranging, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Revised Manuscript: Flower Arranging--American Style, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Teaching Awards, 1977-79 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Included in this container are also cards, newspaper cuts, films and slides, all concerning flower arranging. (Box 3)
- Series 4: Miscellaneous Objects
  - Included in this container are photographs, newspaper cuts, reward certificates and plaques, and so on. (Box 4)